Big news is shaking up the crypto world.
Last week, the Genius Act was signed into law, marking a pivotal moment for the future
of stablecoins and for cryptocurrency exchanges.
The groundbreaking legislation sets strict rules for stablecoin issuers, requiring 100%
reserve backing with liquid assets, monthly public disclosures, and new consumer protection
measures.
It's a game-changer for the industry, bringing legitimacy, transparency, and trust to a space
that's often been clouded by uncertainty.
But what does this mean for crypto exchanges?
The future of stablecoins and the millions of users navigating this rapidly evolving
landscape?
To break it all down, we're joined by two voices from Biconomy.com, a global cryptocurrency
exchange with over 5 million users across 200 countries and regions.
Diane Magnes, senior marketing officer, and Brennos Perandillo, VP of Partnerships, will
share their insights on how the Genius Act is reshaping the industry.
The opportunities it unlocks and how Biconomy.com is staying ahead of the curve.
We'll also dive into the current state of crypto, the ongoing challenges on the horizon
of crypto regulation, and what's next for the future of digital assets?
Welcome to the Defiant Podcast.
Hello, everyone, and welcome back to the Defiant Podcast.
I'm your host, Vinny, and we are joined today by Diane Magnes and Brennos Perandillo.
Thank you so much for being on the podcast, guys.
Thanks for having us, Vinny.
It's a pleasure to be here.
Yeah, so let's jump right in.
So for those of you who may not be familiar, can you give us a quick overview of Biconomy.com
and what sets it apart from other cryptocurrency exchanges?
So our exchange is a centralized crypto exchange, and it was established in 2019.
So we are on the market for five plus years already, and until now, and to this moment,
we are ranked between 20 to 30 centralized crypto exchanges on Bitcoin market cap.
And to be exact, we are 27th at this point.
But you know that rankings jump down and up, so it changes.
And we offer more than 15 products, and usual ones like sports, futures trading, then we
have our specific products that are bicodemicic started by economy-earned products, and many
more like copy trading and trading tools and others, our then 300 coins available for trading
currently, and new coins that listed constantly daily.
And especially now when the market is booming, so at least it's a good, you know, but you
know, also the coins, the ones are listed, and the others are delisted.
So it's a constant flow, but in average, it's 300 coins.
And we are proud for what we have achieved by now.
We have established a lot of partnerships, but on that we'll elaborate more, and then
we have quite solid user base.
It's more than 500K active users on our platform, and actually, yeah, these are our main milestones,
and 30 more will achieve more.
Really Adam?
Yeah, I think that my favorite things about the platform are first, the earned products
that works as a training wheels for users to kind of start playing around with device
stacking and feel what the fine environment would look at, and centralized exchanges are
actually the first platform that a regular user would go through.
But I mean, the main strength from my perspective is our global audience.
We have so many communities, and we communicate in over 20 different languages, locally with
local community managers.
So we grasp this localization, this feeling that each country has, and it varies from
young ones that are here for meme coins, game coins, game tokens, but also for all the way
to the other end of the spectrum of professional traders that want to have automatic trading
and fast trading and reliable charts.
That's really great, because you know, people in different parts of the world are going
to have different needs that crypto can fill, and I think it's easy for us in the US to
get very, you know, tunnel visioned on what we need and not thinking about like, for example,
the USDC, you know, legislation and how that's going to make borderless payments great.
Well, that means a lot more to people in Africa and Latin America than those of us in New York.
So awesome.
So the crypto market has seen many ups and downs lately.
I'd love to hear how you guys would describe the current state of the industry and just
tell us a little bit more about what you're the most excited about as to where the industry
is headed.
It's quite interesting because people perceptions about market and their understanding of market
is different, but I will share, you know, some of my personal views and based on how
we operate in the market.
The current state and the current stage that we are in is very unique because many states,
many governments, they turn to crypto space, crypto industry cannot be ignored any longer.
There were a lot of initiatives that led to that are leading to increasing mass adoption
of crypto among, you know, regular customers, regular people.
So it's very much interesting, you know, introduction of AI tools, AI agents, AI opportunities
in crypto space is also quite immersed.
And even for creating, you know, what does AI is just amazing.
And now with this stage where we are in many things that its health coin season has started
or it's about to start.
So everyone is just on waiting mode to gain as much as they can from this surely a lot
will depend on policies on the US president's policies and actions and, you know, his steps
towards crypto.
The current state is quite promising, I would say.
Absolutely.
Yeah, I will go down on that.
I think the industry and the tech are more mature now and major change is somehow interoperable,
getting better and better every year on that wallets have evolved to be safer and easier.
We have named services, we have best practices that we didn't have three to five years ago.
So this and we see this regulatory frameworks allowing very large institutions to finally
participate in this market, bringing more inclusion and reducing entry barriers for everyone.
I don't know.
I think we are all very, very, very excited about the prognosis of cheaper, faster and
better solutions becoming the dominant service level with stable coins, the defy wallets,
and of course, the whole evolution of on-chain technology.
Absolutely.
And yeah, I think it's interesting, you know, a couple of weeks ago we had Kadena's CEO
on Stuart Popejoy who mentioned, you know, a lot of the time going for efficiency and
cost savings is not necessarily going to be enough to create the buzz that we need, unfortunately.
But I think, you know, like Diane, you were saying, we have not just efficiency, you know,
cheaper, faster transactions.
We're also talking about a potential altcoin season coming up, right?
So if you can have cheaper, faster transactions and make 200% on your doge or whatever that
asset is, like now we're now we're really cooking with gas, you know?
So Diane, I would love to ask you a couple of questions just specifically to, you know,
your marketing experience and how you're working with getting biconomy.com's messages out.
And so the first one being about user experience.
Biconomy.com is known for having a really great user experience, which I think is really important
because exchanges are not just about crypto de-gens, right?
As you said, we're going to have this being the first point of contact for a lot of people
as they are dipping their toes into crypto.
So can you tell us a little bit about how you ensure in your marketing highlights that
this feature is, you know, easy to use?
And how do you do that in order to attract both beginners and experienced DeFi traders?
I would say that simplicity and easy to use features and fast transaction is our super
power and our marketing effects that.
So we have highlight features like intuitive navigation and lighting fast performance through
product videos, then in-app tutorials and we also interact with influencers and we host
our demo sessions from time to time, so for new users, we have created a step-by-step guide
to walk them through a QYC process and to make it easy for them to make their first trade.
If we talk about more experienced users, we have futures and sport interface that is friendly
to them for their level and then we have chat stats and we have push-up notifications for
market updates and our X account is also quite active page or account, whatever you call
it.
So it's also quite active in bringing market insights into where market goes and what
we're talking about performing the best and so on and so forth, but we also have these
extensions on our website and in the application.
So actually, it's just to make it easy, simple and users to learn how to do this, to learn
how to make this process of QLS, to pass it smoothly and then to teach how to trade.
That's great because I feel like there are a lot of people who, their extent of investing
in crypto is buying Bitcoin, maybe buying an NFT, right?
So it's still very much that kind of first level of investment and so it's really awesome
to see that there are resources to help people who, okay, maybe I bought Bitcoin and I want
to learn about earning yields or I want to learn about farming or whatever it is because
I think those are the things that can come off as scary even to the people who have believed
in crypto for a while.
So that's really great.
And then moving into what it's like to market in a regulated environment, I think this year
is really unique in the sense that we have multiple bills that are being passed across
the world to help protect consumers and to give us the guideposts that we need in order
to continue to innovate.
So with the Genius Act introducing marketing rules to protect consumers, how is biconomy.com
adapting its marketing strategies to align with the new regulations?
I guess this regulation, sorry, is awesome actually because it protects consumers first
of all and this is our top priority to protect users, to protect their funds, to make it safe
for them to trade.
We actually practically built compliance first marketing workflow and that comes especially
for the US and allied jurisdictions.
So all promotional content now with that bill is being reviewed just to ensure that we avoid
exaggerated claims for our users.
So for example, we've shifted language in certain promotional materials, you know, from
earn quickly just to trade cautiously and so on and so forth.
And we also embedded risk disclaimers in all major campaigns throughout this time.
So we are now updating also our geopolitical targeting rules and we will move non-compliant
features in sort of sensitive markets.
So actually we believe that this helps us build trust while we stay ahead of regulatory
expectations.
And for us, you know, if a user is not compliant to trading rules that were earlier also introduced
by other regulations, earlier regulations, then we inform the trader that, you know,
you are not compliant, you need to readjust your strategy.
So if they don't do that, then we imply certain measures also.
So this is also an effort to comply with regulations.
And there is a lot to be done actually on compliance, especially in light of these
Genius Act.
I believe that we've done what we could until now and we are moving, we're still doing
and we'll be doing what we can do to protect our users and to save their funds.
Yeah, and I imagine it must be a big workload to, you know, stay up to date with each of
the regions that you're covering and, you know, what's legal here, what's illegal there,
what are you allowed to say and do.
So it's a big undertaking, you know, and the ways in which the Genius Act, yes, will obviously
impact your U.S. customer base, but who knows what the tailwinds are going to be there.
So yeah, really important and I like that you're building on creating trust with the
consumer base because that's, that's what we need in crypto, right?
Like the worst thing that can happen is someone buys cryptocurrency and then it's lost or
something negative happens.
Like a lot of people just need one bad experience and they're out, you know?
So it's really important, I think, to work on not only building loyalty with your consumer
base, but trust so that they want to be loyal to you, otherwise, like who cares.
Yeah, I agree with you.
All right, so I'm just going to shift over to you, Brenna.
Let's talk a little bit about partnerships in crypto.
They're obviously a crucial part of any business, but especially here in the crypto space.
Can you share any of your recent collaborations that you feel have been really exciting or
that have significantly impacted by economy.com's growth?
Yeah, but it's, you know, it's hard to pinpoint one specific partnership.
The way we look at it, each collaboration positively impacts our growth, actually token
insurers.
I would say first and foremost, talking with token insurers and understanding why they're
coming to us, what they expect from it.
We truly believe the way that we deliver market access, but we also believe the way that we
communicate with each, I mean, with each community, so a token being listed, they're bringing our
community to us.
They need to believe in everything that the system has worked properly, but also we will
bring them to our communities and to different countries and to understand what are the core
values they want to communicate, how they connect with them, what's their branding, the tone
of voice, all of these things that we will represent them in a sort of way.
But some interesting things are also offering staking to non-dax users, like I mentioned
before through the earned action that users have access to those specific tokens and they
see that as they're saving accounts sometimes, depending on which country they are.
They have a hurdle of doing with currency devaluation every single day.
So going through crypto, even sometimes certain need forms of being around and not as volatile
anymore, they could be an interesting tool for them if they're accepted in their regions.
But part of the conversation that takes a regular block of our calendars are regularly
reaching out to L1s and L2s, some VCs, some market makers, and specific communities.
To understand their sentiment about the whole market, what they're looking at, especially
with L1s and L2s, because they are the protocols, they are the home of everything that is being
built, what is there that we need to be ready to integrate soon, or is there any way that
we can help them to access certain markets or even to get feedback from certain user
communities. And of course, we're going to talk more and more about it, but now there's
a very strong new stream of stablecoins, but they're looking for liquidity and additional
trading pairs because they want to have market access.
And some of them will try to compete with already large, very large, and well-established
stablecoin issues. But some of those are trying to solve specific use cases in different regions
of the globe.
I think it's so important to footnote, right? Like a Bitcoiner and a Dogecoin, Maxi, are
not the same consumer a lot of the time. And kind of trying to figure out what do these
people need, and for the generalist crypto investor, you and I were talking before about
how, yeah, some of us just want to diversify our bags and have lots of things going for
us, right? So they're just like in any industry related to finance. There's so many different
consumers and like going to them to ask for what they want and what they need. That just
always goes a lot better than being like, here's what you need. Buy it.
Yeah. And most of the time that that behavior doesn't help, right? It doesn't work. You
need to be listening and be to be attentive.
Yeah, not the best attitude, but you know, well, we're community first often. As cringes
that can sound sometimes in crypto, I do think it captures a lot of like us changing what
the expectation is of like the relationships between different entities.
The PR Genius is a top crypto PR and growth marketing agency, helping brands globally
with expert PR and strategic growth marketing. They've worked with 300 plus projects like
movement labs and IO.net. Unlike traditional agencies, they charge only on performance.
The services include earned PR opportunities and marketing services to help boost wallet
holders and organic ex followers. Learn more at www.the PR genius.com.
So let's talk a little bit more about stable coins because another thing that happened
with the Genius Act is now it opens the door for banks and for other entities to become
licensed stable coin users issuers, which is pretty exciting.
Do you see this affecting partnerships and competition in the crypto exchange space?
Yeah, well, for sure it raises the bar and pushes the whole market forward. That's it.
And hopefully it will raises the new tide will raise all boats with it. But let me hope
is that Micron, Europe, Genius and Clarity acts in US will make trade fine banks to finally
properly embrace web3 instead of just turning their backs to it. And to this date, there
are still very large corporations that completely block any interactions with web3 businesses
or even users. Yeah, talk about attitude. Right. So that's
the first thing that I want to see change because this is many people say, Oh, yeah,
I want to do that. But my bank of choice or my two or three bank of choices don't integrate
to to whatever you're offering or this specific game or this specific solution that I've felt
attracted to. But I believe also that very quickly these rules will bring better integration.
I think that's the first thing that we'll see. We'll see instant transfers. When we start
thinking and you mentioned this before, most people in America don't think too much about
it because most of the systems in America work really well. Now the countries in the
world might share the same feeling, but most of the world struggles with anything financial
related. Some people still need to physically go to a bank branch agency that is far, far
away. And then you have a specific time that you need to go there and that disrupts your
working schedule, your family schedule. If you're a large business that has cross border
operations, or if you are a supplier somewhere, an exporter, hurdles and more hurdles, not
only with governmental rulings, but the whole banking system that it's still doing the same
thing as 50 or maybe even 100 years ago. And let's not forget that the first use case
besides Bitcoin or blockchain is being bringing trust to the system. So it would be more safe
for everybody.
Yeah, exactly. Speaking of safety, I'd love to talk a little bit more about security.
It's obviously a big priority for my economy, as Diane was saying earlier. Do you ever use
partnerships as an opportunity to enhance the platform security measures? And if so, what
does that look like?
Every single time. Every discussion. Every conversation. It will start with, of course,
mapping expectations and opportunities and finding synergies. But the next step, the
next evolution, whenever the conversation gets serious is due diligence is each establishing
trust on each side and then evolving to the fact that do we want to associate our brands?
Do you want to be publicly together? Do we want to have our logo appear on each other's
websites and communicate throughout their communities? So that and every single time
there's a little bit that back and forth that it brings to our compliance or legal or the
marketing to say, we're doing this. Could we do that? Or why are we doing this? How do
I justify? I have this question. Let's jump on the same discussion and share why we think
about this.
So each partnership is a building block of trust against. We're always validating each
other. And I like to say that whoever is present in this industry for more than four years can
easily note how most of the exhibitors change every two years in the conference floor. So
that's one thing. If you've been around, you know at least each brand validates each other.
I love that. It's like DYOR or bust is like so crypto. And yeah, it's just so great to
me that, you know, like so many people in crypto, especially those of us who are like trying
to build a better financial system, build a better world, you know, as, you know, utopian
as that might sound, like the legislation is actually just catching up to us. Like we've
already been doing due diligence. We've already been doing like all of the work that you need
to do to create a secure platform. This is just helping hopefully to weed out bad actors
and to add that additional those guardrails that, you know, a lot of us have been asking
for for over a decade, right? So it's exciting to finally have it. It might not be enough,
but government is slow, unfortunately. So I'd love to switch back. I'll ask these questions
to both of you, either of you whoever wants to jump in. Let's talk a little bit about
the genius acts impact on crypto exchanges because there's a new focus on reserve banking
and on transparency, you know, transparency being a great part of the crypto industry.
How do you think Reserve banking and transparency will impact the way exchanges like biconomy.com
operate? I don't mind, Brenna, if you stop. Okay. So polite. Thanks. I think you just,
you answered the question before asking it. I don't see much change for the exchanges individually.
Yeah, because most of us are already focused on best practices. We needed to be, we needed
to build trust in the market. And honestly, it's extremely competitive. This is a market
that anybody can jump in. You know, you have all kinds of trading platforms. You can build
a white label that is not so expensive. The expensive part of the things not necessarily
the back end of the system is all the talent that you need to hire and spending time and
knowledge to put the effort. But I would say to put the effort to make something proper
and compliant. But I would mention one thing, legal and compliance department, we need to
define what the diligence looks like when stable coin issuers in America are under the act.
But then we will also have issues from other jurisdictions under different regulations.
Do we need to build walls? Is this interesting for the industry? We might evaluate things
like we can have restrictions according to geolocation or KYC for specific regions.
But I don't think that that would be the best outcome out of it. I think we need to
search for more unity than separation. That's my two cents on this.
Oh, you know, yeah, you are taking it as unity actually. But if we talk about this
genius act, you know, yes, certainly it brings transparency and clarity into crypto space.
And this is what it was lacking actually. So now if you could just repeat the question
because there was a lot of question and now I'm a bit close. Yeah, no worries.
So the question was how does the genius acts focus on reserve banking and transparency
impact the way exchanges like biconomy.com operate? So yeah, I see. But for me, you know,
I would say that exchanges would still need to more effort. You know, to make this QIS
QIC process obligatory, you know, if some of them haven't done it yet. Because for us,
it's a must have because you are not fully functional without this feature. And if you
are not identified, you cannot withdraw money or trade and do because it's whatever.
Actually, these helps to protect the users, the customers. And it helps to battle these
scams and the various, you know, if we talk about P2P trading, it also helps to tackle
those that characters, characters easily. And, you know, also for US, US citizens now,
as certain exchanges will need more transparency and more, you know, maybe they will require
some documents that prove their residence, you know, to be sure that this is a US citizen
or US resident. And we need to do something about this because we need to comply with
this act now. So I would say it helps. It brings these clarity and transparency, but
it also requires certain efforts, you know, to build and to rearrange sort of current
things for users. Yeah, absolutely. And I've already seen changes in some of the exchanges.
You know, I was buying some crypto on Coinbase and then all of a sudden they were like, oh,
sorry, you can't pay with your debit card anymore. You have to link your bank account.
And so that's, you know, less than a week, less than a week from the Genius Act passing.
So it's, it's cool to see that people are going to be like moving very quickly in order
to comply with the new regulation. And I think that's a really great sign because, you know,
no one wants to get sued. Nobody wants the SEC knocking on their door, right? So I, so
I'll be curious to see like what else changes because that's something that's to be kind
of not very consequential. But I think as we continue to see, you know, like not only
the Genius Act, but the Clarity Act and other legislation being passed around the world,
will be interesting to see how quickly people change. And then, of course, what new challenges
will inevitably spring up. This is crypto after all. So staying a little bit on the, the Genius
Act, what do you see as like the future of stable coins? Like there's obviously going
to be a very big shift happening now that we have all this regulation, a lot of mainstream
news covering stable coins. So how is Bicon be preparing to stay ahead of the evolving
market as the role of stable coins also continues to mature?
A few things that we're looking at, it's not only the stable coin acts and clarity, but
we've been discussing a lot. And I think that we'll see a lot of our dreams becoming reality that
probably we're going towards a direction that every single application will be
single, the seamlessly embedded or connector are integrated to a web3 wallet. And there's also
very, a secondary, very strong trend of tokenization, like the tokenization of everything,
putting the whole world on chain. And that comes in different levels, but most of it is already
happening here at a small scale. We can, we know and we can see projects that are already
tokenizing airline, sorry, airline mileage, gas station, grocery points program, loyalty programs,
e-sports are already born into this tag automation, art certificates, all NFTs, but
chains of custody with pharmaceuticals, all of these sports betting is now becoming
prediction markets and all types of betting are becoming a prediction market. But there's a lot
of new trains that are natively or native on chain and all that connects on blockchain and has a
token. Therefore, you can have your own web3 wallet, you have your address that will be soon enough
connected to your bank account through single coins. So everything will move instantly between
these things. But the main thing that brings that comes to my head when I look into this is we're
seeing a popularization of AI agents and AI, these agents, they're not going to talk to a customer
support service from a bank agency. They talk tokens, they talk blockchain, they move at a speed
that it's not human and they move, they do that and they're such a high volume. So as people get
and these applications become more supported by AI agents, this is the fact that these agents,
this is the financial technology, this is the financial tech stack that these AI agents will
use. The way that we are, I think, yeah, I'm wearing this, is at bacunaby.com we're preparing
for this. First thing, first of all, understanding what our users like and what they want more of.
And noticing their behavior, paying attention to their journey in our platform, where they're
coming from, which kind of iterations and experimentations we make that they react. Well, quests,
engagements, giveaways, and this understanding is the driver for us to decide where our development
team or Indian years will spend their efforts to improve the tech stack. This is also how our
marketing campaigns change. And this will define, this is something that I discussed regularly with
the team on which new integrations we need. What are the partners that I need to start pursuing
to make our users happy? Thank you with all that in mind. That's great. Diane, anything to add?
Yeah, I fully support what Brandon just said. You know, for me, yeah, it's obvious that
this act will move stable coins, will move them beyond just trading. They will become, you know,
the like tools for general users, you know, and for us to, as an exchange actually, because there
will be sort of verified stable coins that we can give an access to our platform. And those that
will not be sort of recognized, then surely we cannot focus on them. So it will depend how the
things will develop. But I agree with Brandon that our main focus will be on what our people,
what our users, what our traders and community members would like to see on our platform.
So we are adjusting our policies towards this. And okay, yeah, users based best interest.
Yes, I love that because there's just so many options out there that it can be very overwhelming.
And so it's nice to have people who are qualified to be doing research and like putting this
directly into their business model, I think is something that a lot of people are going to
really flock to because, you know, we all have that like too much freedom becomes a little bit
like strangling. So it'll be a team effort going back to the unity idea team effort to push this
all forward. And I mean, you're already seeing, you know, different exchanges offering yield on
stable coins that far surpasses what's available for a savings account. I think in the US, it's like
half a percent is the average yield that you can get in a high yield savings account in a savings
account. It's like, that's not even beating inflation. Like why would what's the point of that? And I'm
seeing USD go down in value, right? So it's like, it's kind of, I think when we look at how having to,
you know, peg USDC to USD, for example, that'll help the dollar. But I think when you have these
different tools that are offering higher yield, some places are offering, you know, 4%, some places
are as crazy as 20% yield, you know, so it's like, yeah, those are numbers people are going to listen
to. Diane, I'd love to switch to talking a little bit about the mobile app and just kind of what
your guys' thoughts are on mobile first defy. It's definitely something that's gaining traction. I
think in a lot of ways, because we have apps like Robinhood making mobile so much a part of their
business offering that it's like, you know, easy on the go trading. So it's definitely a key feature
in that sense. And Diane, I'd love to hear other any strategies that have been the most effective
in driving app engagement, app downloads and just helping consumers with mobile. Yeah, we are
constantly promoting, you know, our app, our application. But what we've done, when it was,
it was first developed, we launched a campaign, where we offered the people who uploaded,
will upload our app. We offered them some rewards. And now, even lately, just recently,
we had campaigns when we requested and people users to rate our application in Google app and
Google Play. And then you have this iPhone app story. So yeah, we requested our users,
and we offered this opportunity to them because if they rate, they get reward. And this is sort of
incentive for our users who use our application on a daily basis. And what do we also do in marketing,
are we like a banner, a banner, you know, it was an active promoter of our application,
when we participated in a number of offline exhibitions and crypto events. So it was also one of the
tools that we used. But besides that, it's a constant promotion. I wouldn't say that there
was a particular strategy that gave us a certain percentage. But when we launched these campaigns,
helped us to onboard a lot of users. So actually, when you offer people sort of some incentive,
reward, and so on, so they are more inclined to do things that you would like them to do. So
it's of course, yeah, it helps us to promote the app. We still understand that there is still a
lot to do for our application to make it even better for our users. So constant collaboration
between tier and marketing and technological. What if sending crypto felt more human? Pulse just
launched red packets, a new way to gift tokens with meaning. It's gasless, gamified, and
claimable inside group chats only. Think air drops meet social cues on chain. Backed by smart wallet
tech and live across major L2s, red packets turned communities into microeconomies of gratitude and
growth. No seed phrases, no friction, just connection with value. Check it out at pulse dot social.
So Diane, I know you've been marketing crypto for a long time before Bicommy.com. You're at
Binance. I'd love to hear just what are you the most excited about as far as working in marketing
in this industry in 2025? Like we have legislation, we have new all time highs every day. It seems
like with Bitcoin, like it just feels like we're in a very different world than we were previously.
So, yeah, given your experience in marketing for crypto exchanges for many years, like what are
you the most excited about in the current moment? Wow, really interesting. Hard to narrow it down,
I know. Besides Bitcoin going to the moon, what are you excited about? Yeah, that's the most
important one. You know, what the most people are excited about and be inclusive. But actually,
yeah, crypto space is completely different from what it was before. And it's a whole industry now.
It's a fully fledged industry and it brings in too many people. But what I'm excited about is
that crypto is so dynamic. For me, no other interest in the world brings these dynamic
changes into your everyday life. You know, it's so instant. It's very, well, it's very volatile and
things change very fast in crypto and you will sometimes feel like you are somewhere behind
with all the developments. Oh, yes. Yeah, so this drives me actually and I like crypto
for this. But as we speak about, I am sort of scared, but I'm also talking about AI, AI opportunities
that are available at the moment for various functions and things to do AI. And yeah,
I would say that that's what can give us what we can't even expect at this moment. And it's scary.
For me, it's it's still scary what AI can do, but it gives immerse. Yeah, I'm going to be really
interested to see how like I definitely think crypto is doing really well because it has the
possibility of writing that the wave of AI. But you know, I'm most interested to see, I think that
crypto technology, blockchain technology is probably our best tool against AI, like going off the rails.
And so I'll be curious to see, you know, there are different companies that are engaging with like,
you know, zero knowledge privacy, they're talking about how we can commodify, you know, online data
and stuff like that and doing it through tokens. So I think it'll be really interesting to see
not only the kinds of, you know, tokens and and financial tools that come out of the collaboration
and crypto and AI, but just it might be crypto that that helps to keep AI in check. Like, I have
believed that for many years so far. And if the government won't do it, somebody's got a,
and I guess it'll be the crypto bros again, saving the day.
So switching back over to you, Breno, I would love to just hear, are there any trends within the
crypto space that you are picking up on and that you're like, particularly zoned in on for 2025.
So many think that we're finally, we're finally reaching this in UI. I think that's the first day.
We have proper UI that people don't need to go through a very long learning curve anymore.
Also, the people can have a crypto wallet with their phone biometrics. That's the first thing.
We do we are reaching real interoperability between chains that it's not so clunky.
If I bought an NFT here and I want to trade it for something else, I need to go through different
platforms to do it. It stops getting better. And then we have AI agents that are learning
everything. And soon enough, they'll be better than us doing these things. And then we just ask
them to execute whatever we want. But there are two things that I think we've been seeing major
movements towards. So we also happen with meme coins recently passed. And we, we see decentralized
platforms going from amazing to bad and back to amazing again, like the funds of the world and
their token emissions. There are a few things that touch that point because those are cultural
movements. There is and I've been reading into how strong it is the tipping culture these days
and how we have decentralized social protocols. So whatever we're seeing happening on Twitch,
it would be very easy to morph into something that is web3 native. And we have some examples of that
already taken over. So making it easy for everybody to create a token out of a conversation or a
picture, you have a family day that you go to sports that. And you want to collect that. And
that's a new type of collectible. And of course, for us, we want to be the environment that makes
integrates all of it. If you want to train this, collect if you're going to hold it in a safe way,
that's why platforms like us exist. And the other way, the other thing that I can't forget to mention
especially when we think about being about a global presence is providing access for everybody to
financial tools. We keep touching these points, but we have to remind ourselves that in certain
areas, if you're not an accredited investor, you don't have access to certain yields like you were
mentioning. You have to you have your savings accounts from your bank that is boring, that is
under the inflation rates, that it's pushed by somebody, some manager that has their own quota to
reach. And right here, okay, there's risk and big numbers will have higher risk. But there are
right with especially with the regulation coming through, there are stable ways or safer ways
to earn yield or at least to be protected from the currency devaluation or to build sturdy future
plans that you trust they will come through instead of just placing bets all over the place.
Right. Well, more strategic would definitely be great. And you know, we were talking before the
podcast about, you know, obviously the Clarity Act is right here on the horizon. So I'd love to
hear Breno like, we have the Genius Act in the bag. Awesome. What are you most excited for as far
as what will happen after the Clarity Act? Hopefully gets passed. I think that the worst part of the
industry are the bad actors. And it's still too easy to say. This is a very complicated technology.
You should just trust my words. And everybody ordinary Joe's just need to some of them trust.
If you play the numbers game, there's always a small percentage of people that will fall short
for these things and believe whatever a random person is telling them. And we've been seeing
this throughout centuries. This is not related to any type of financial technology or technology
of some sort. I think, I don't know who said it, but I saw some people saying this and I keep
going back to the fact that I'm excited about what we don't know yet. But there's a lot of new
solutions coming to old problems probably that will be built on top of all these regulations
that now a lot of people that were avoiding this market or that had opinions but couldn't act on
them will feel welcome. And we're eager to do more. We understand the fact we've been struggling
for a few years to keep growing and to prove that there's a reason for us to be here. And I think
that's the best to come. There was something else with the Clarity Act that's not coming to my hand
right now. You'll have to send it to me offline. Yeah, you know, going back to Diane, I'd love to
hear your thoughts on this. Like, you're so right, Breno, that idea of like, not your keys, not your
crypto. Like, yes, there's a learning curve, but just do it. Like putting all this responsibility
on the consumer, it literally never works. Like something we have to borrow from marketing is like
the assumption that the consumer is lazy, the assumption that, you know, you've got to make
10 to 15 impressions on someone before they actually interact with your brand. Like all the
stuff that we know about marketing, we know because it's based on human psychology. Like,
it's something that I've really kind of butted heads with with people where they just want to,
like, this is the great technology and everyone just has to adapt to it. It's like, no, things
were not because they're difficult, but because under the hood, they're very complex. But the U,
the UX, the UI is super easy. Like smartphones, right? The desktop, like all this stuff that connects
us to the internet and connects us to each other, you make it so easy to use. Like, that's what makes
it popular. So yeah, I think I think that conversation is like starting to happen. I see people starting
to be like, okay, well, actually, maybe we should just make this easier and stop, you know, shaming
people for not caring about whatever the upside is. That's exactly. And I was thinking about this.
I think that's the thing. I think I just brought it back to my to me is let's see everybody using
crypto vacations without knowing. I mean, it's happening in the back of your application. You
don't need to see it. I want it to be like, you know, fourth of July, we're flipping beyond burgers.
And people are like, wow, this cheeseburger tastes great. Is it Wagyu? And I'm like, it's vegan. Ha.
Like, that's the type of thing, you know, where you like literally can't tell. That's.
So, okay, Diane might disagree. But to start wrapping up, same question to both of you. I'll
give it to you, Diane, first. What is next for Biconomy.com? Are there any exciting developments,
features, anything coming up that you'd love our audience to be aware of? Yeah, actually,
yeah, as a crypto space is evolving, we are also developing constantly. First, we are developing
our blockchain and we have announced it earlier. So it's still in the development phase, but
we are working on this. We have launched recently, but we are still working on the this AI, AI trading
tool, which will help our traders and users to to trade more efficiently and smart, smartly.
So now we will definitely do more partnerships. That's, yeah, Brella knows this. And but we are
aiming at, you know, from the technological side, because we cannot forget about technology as well
for the last year, 2020, we've done many, many upgrades, system upgrades. So we are working on
this constantly and it's in the plants. Also, we cannot not to upgrade the system and so on to
make it fast reliable and safe. And for promotional activities, we are also planning many campaigns
to attract new users and to keep our current users also. As for participation in different
crypto events offline, you know, for our users to meet personally with our team
and to be aware and make them sure that we are real people who are there and we are not just
sort of AI agents somewhere in the space. So we will continue with this effort and our
is being built up for the next half six months this year. And so these are actually we will continue
listing objects that we see them as strong or, you know, like trending in the market or those
that our users would like to see on our platform. So this work will continue. Wonderful. And how
about you, Breno, any partnerships in the pipeline that you can share with us? That I can share.
So I don't know. Yeah, we have. I mean, well, we'll take doxing as well. You know, this is
this is defiant after all. Give us that alpha. There's something coming. There are some some
big things coming. We're having fun discussions. Very, very interesting. And this is I think I would
I would highlight three areas that I'm looking forward to to see, you know, solidifying throughout
this next week's months to come as more integrations to having very good discussions. We're learning
and we're figuring out certain integrations that will be that at the end of the day, it's all about
bringing utility to our users or to certain communities. The second thing is I am extremely
excited about it. I know that I should be scared, but I'm more excited than scared. Every time I
think about there are tons of things that I want to do. And I don't do many of them because there's
not enough time, and especially rebalancing my wallets or organizing portfolio, looking at getting
the last updates of certain projects or certain systems or certain protocols. With AI, it became
so much easier. And the tools that we're developing will make this easier inside our platform,
which is already directly created. So you can just adjust your automated trading agent.
So I want to see this become taking body and becoming in reality. But also, and I kept thinking
about this. I think after after the ONFC Lisbon event, I have one conversation. I had one conversation
that was we do everything fast and try to do as much as we can online. So we can save the time
that we spend together in in real life events. And I think that's how we kind of get the circle,
you know, and one thing kind of brings new fuel to have this energy and keep moving fast as much
as we can. Yeah, I love that. I mean, you can't you really can't underestimate the power of bringing
people together and allowing the social interaction to be the thing that leads it. I mean, Brenna,
that's how we met in beautiful Lisbon. So like, yeah, we've been online for a long time, you know,
crypto has been mostly online for a long time. So like, I'm really excited for what Diane,
you were talking about about integrating consumers with the team, what you're talking about, Brenna,
just like, yeah, freeing up our our headspace so we can really just be in the moment. Because that's
that's the hardest thing to do. For sure. All right, guys, well, thank you so much for joining us
here at the Defiant. Where can our audience find you guys? And where can they learn more about
by economy? We've got many many socials and ex ex or former Twitter. We are very active on that
platform. We have a telegram group where we're also daily communicating with our users and solving
the issues if they need them. Then we have many more social accounts. And then I told me, you know,
it's a Reddit and Discord and many others website website is a source of information,
official information about our exchange, triple w dot by economy dot com. You can find us there
and upload another app. And we are also there. So it's available on Android, on Apple system. So
well, everywhere you can find us easily. Yeah, that's yeah, that's x dot com slash by economy
com or official website has everything else by economy dot com. Then you find several telegram
groups in different languages is everything, the score, all the platforms are there. I love
so much that you guys are multi lingual because like, that's something that a lot of people have
complained to me about working in crypto media for as long as I have, they're like, everything's in
English. And you know, a lot is lost in translation. Absolutely. It's hard enough to translate,
you know, a casual conversation, let alone something as nuanced as this. Thank you so much,
Diane and Brano for coming on. And we'll be following what comes next from biconomy.com.
Thank you. This was really fun. Thank you for your invitation. Of course. And hope to have you guys
back soon. If you enjoyed this episode, be sure to like and subscribe for more content like this.
And join us next Friday when we'll be talking to Jordan Jefferson, founder and CEO of My Doge
about how upgrades to the Dogecoin protocol can upgrade it from a meme coin to a competitive
platform for DAPs and DeFi just in time for DeFi Summer 2.0. But in the meantime, stay tuned,
stay informed, stay defiant.